<document>
  <properties>
    <title>Changes Web Service Generator</title>
    <author email="fady@legsem.com">Fady Moussallam</author>
  </properties>
  <body>
    <release version="1.2.0" date="2008-08-01" description="Velocity macros and Proxies generation">
      <action dev="fady" type="add">
        The Generator can now produce Web Service proxies for mainframe clients. These
        can be deployed with the legstar-c2wsrt runtime to provide mainframe programs
        with the ability to call oubound Web Services.
        In this case, the generator produces a Servlet and a COBOL sample client.
      </action>
      <action dev="fady" type="update">
        The XSLT based generation has been replaced by Velocity macros. The code is
        easier to maintain and performances are better.
        There is a new legstar-cixsgen-model project that isolates classes that are
        common to multiple target platforms (Jaxws, Mule, ...).
        The Ant Task has been renamed Jaxws2CixsGenerator to show the dependency on
        Jaxws. There are also minor changes in the Task properties so old Ant script
        may break with this new version.
        Test cases have been revised and are more thorough.
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="1.1.0" date="2007-08-30" description="CICS Containers support">
      <action dev="fady" type="add">
        Operations now support multiple inputs and multiple outputs where each input or
        output structure maps to a different JAXB object and also to a CICS Container.
      </action>
    </release>
    
    <release version="1.0.1" date="2007-04-20" description="Transport/Connectivity refactoring">
      <action dev="fady" type="add">
        Generated endpoints now use a new XML configuration file. It is called legstar-invoker-config.xml
        and should be accessible from the classpath (for instance stored in shared/classes).
      </action>
      <action dev="fady" type="add">
        Generated endpoints are protocol agnostic. You can switch from http to socket and
        have both direct or pooled sessions to CICS by changing the XML configuration file.
      </action>
      <action dev="fady" type="remove">
        The Hostconnection.properties file no longer exist. It is not referenced from the
        generated endpoints anymore (content is replaced by XML configuration file).
      </action>
    </release>

    <release version="0.0.1" date="2006-12-31" description="First release">
      <action dev="fady" type="add">
        First version of the generator.
      </action>
    </release>
  </body>
</document>