<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<!DOCTYPE book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.4//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.4/docbookx.dtd">
<section id="jaxwsgen-using-eclipse-adapter">
<title>Mainframe Adapter generation</title>
<para>
  The final step in the process is to generate a Mainframe Adapter, which is a JAX-WS Endpoint.
</para>
<para>
  The first stage is to perform a mapping between the target mainframe program and a Java side operation.
  This is option <emphasis>LegStar->New operations mapping…</emphasis> On the first page you select a name and location for
  the mapping file. Operations mapping files are XML files with the <emphasis>cixs</emphasis> extension.
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen new operation</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-new-operation.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  Clicking on Finish creates the operations mapping file and then opens up a special editor associated
  with files with cixs extension:
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen editor</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-editor.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  Click on the add button to start the operations mapping dialog:
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen operation mapping</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-operation-mapping.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  Type in an operation name and then enter the target mainframe program name. This must correspond to an
  actual mainframe program.
</para>
<para>
  The next step is to specify input and output structures. You will have to use the add button again.
  You are then presented with the JAXB classes that you generated previously:
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen structures mapping</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-structures-mapping.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  The target LSFILEAE CICS program is commarea-driven, there is a single input and a single output
  which both happen to be described by the same COBOL structure. So all we have to do is to select
  Dfhcommarea both for input and output.
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen operation mapping done</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-operation-mapping-done.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  This dialog allows you to specify a different input and output structures if needed. It also allows
  you to specify more than one input and more than one output as it would be the case for a target
  container-driven program (using CICS channel/containers) for instance.
</para>
<para>
  Back on the editor, you can now click on the generate button and should see the following dialog:
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen select target</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-select-target.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  The operations mapping editor can be used with different kinds of generators, which are registered
  dynamically on your machine. Depending on your configuration, you might have more than one possible
  generation target. In our case, we want to generate a <emphasis>Mainframe Adapter</emphasis>.
  When you select that target and click the OK button you get this final dialog:
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen parameters</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-parameters.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
    The generation process needs to create various artifacts, including Java classes that implement a
    JAX-WS endpoint bundled in a J2EE war file. This dialog allows you to select the target locations and
    other options. Most of these options have default values derived from your preferences. You can change
    the proposed parameters as you see fit.
</para>
<para>
    Again, the Finish button creates an ant script, which actually generates the artifacts. The ant script
    has a name similar to build-jaxws-j2c-CustomerService.xml.
</para>
<figure>
<title>Adapter service generation screen results</title>
<mediaobject>
<imageobject>
<imagedata fileref="images/eclipse-screen-shot-adapter-service-generation-result.jpg" format="JPG" scalefit="1" width="100%" contentdepth="100%"/>
</imageobject>
</mediaobject>
</figure>
<para>
  Besides the JAX-WS java classes, you will also find ant scripts that were generated to help you with
  deploying your endpoint. build-jar.xml bundles the classes in a jar archive that you could deploy to
  AXIS2 for instance. build-war.xml bundles a war file suitable for Sun's JAX-WS RI (Metro).
</para>
<para>
  Once deployed, you can use the Web Service with any SOAP client such as 
  <ulink url="http://www.soapui.org/">soapUI</ulink>.
</para>
</section>
